Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Abner Berry, 1974-1977; cuid1186 (Box 12, Cd Berry 1-6, Box 1, Cassette 16 A-F)
    Berry also discusses the activities of the CP and its interactions with other organizations. This includes his activities and politics in Politburo in the late 1930s; analysis of the trade union caucuses, including Mike Quill and the TWU; the reactions to the Nazi-Soviet Pact; the foundation of the National Negro Congress; experiences working with Garvey movement; and the work of the Ethiopian Defense Committee in Harlem. Berry also describes the Party's working relationships with ministers, including Adam Clayton Powell (Baptist), Johnny Johnson (Episcopalian), Father Phillips (Episcopalian), William Lloyd Imes (Presbyterian), and Father Divine.
    Other topics addressed include the CP education programs for members in Harlem, the high turnover among CP members, differences in debate of African-American self-determination in North and South of United States, the activities of the Workers' Alliance at the Home Relief Bureaus, Unemployed Councils, and interracial marriage in the Party.
    Interview by Mark Naison.
  - Steve Beumer, Mar 11, 1975; cuid1187 (Box 12, Cd Beumer 1-4, Box 1, Cassette 17 A-C)
    Interview covers Beumer's family background in Indiana, his political activities there and in Detroit during the late 1960s-1970s, the Socialist Workers Party, and his experiences as bus driver and union activist in Detroit.
    Interview by Claudia Hommel.
    Duration: 219 minutes in three parts
  - Martin Birnbaum, Nov 6, 1977; cuid1188 (Box 12, Cd Birnbaum 1-2, Box 1, Cassette 18 A-B)
    Interview documents the life and activities of a Yiddish "proletarian poet" including his childhood, immigration and literary work for New Yorker Volkszeitung during the 1920s, his friendship with writer Moshe Nadir, the role of the Left in the Yiddish literary community, the Proletpen circle of writers, Birnbaum's disillusionment with Communism and poetic realism, and his return to unrestrained lyricism.
    Duration: 96 minutes in two parts
  - Martin Birnbaum, Feb 5, 1978; cuid1189 (Box 1, Cassette 18 C, Box 12, Cd Birnbaum 3)
    Duration: 58 minutes
  - Martin Birnbaum, Feb 16, 1983; cuid1190 (Box 12, Cd Birnbaum 4, Box 1, Cassette 19)
    Interview covers the meaning of the "sense of humor" in Yiddish literary work and Birnbaum's own sense of humor contrasted with that of writer Moshe Nadir and Jewish popular culture.
    Duration: 17 minutes
  - Violet Wainio Bjong, Jul 7, 1984; cuid1191 (Box 12, Cd Bjong 1, Box 79, Cassette 265)
    Interview covers the activities of Wainio Bjong's father and mother, Finnish-American radical leaders during the 1920s-1930s, her activities in Fitchburg, Massachusetts during the 1930s, work on a Left-oriented daily in Fitchburg, life in Brooklyn cooperative housing, and reflections.
    Duration: 65 minutes
  - Fred Blair, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1192 (Box 1, Cassette 20, Box 12, Cd Blair 1, Box 7, Folder 6)
    Interview covers the role of ethnicity in Communist Party of Wisconsin during the 1930s-1940s; support of the Left from the Polish sector dating back to 1880 and support of other Slav groups from 1910s; role of Meta Berger in Wisconsin Party and Blair's ascendency to state leadership; unemployment demonstration in Milwaukee and influence on students in University of Wisconsin-Madison; increase of District membership with addition of northern Wisconsin; character of northern Wisconsin rural Communists; exodus of rural Communists from state during the 1940s-1950s, and the impact of McCarthyism on the decline of Communist Party support.
  - Norman Bloomfield, May 7, 1983; cuid1193 (Box 12, Cd Bloomfield 1, Box 1, Cassette 21)
    Interview topics include the Young People's Socialist League during the 1930s; Trotskyism; the University of California, Berkeley campus; and work in shipyards.
  - Grace Lee Boggs, Mar 28, 1983; cuid1194 (Box 1, Cassette 22-22 A, Box 12, Cd G. Boggs 1-2)
    The interview includes a discussion of Boggs' Asian-American family background in Providence, Rhode Island; her education and involvement in radical politics in New York during the late 1930s; the Workers Party and Johnson-Forest tendency during the 1940s; Correspondence in Detroit during the 1950s; involvement in the Black Power movement with her husband, James Boggs; and comments on C.L.R. James.
  - Grace Lee Boggs, Aug 6, 1986; cuid1195 (Box 10, Cassette 420 A-B, Box 12, Cd G. Boggs 3-4)
    Topics discussed include entry into radical politics, the Johnson-Forest Tendency, and the relationship of culture and the Left.
    Interview by Ellen Kellman.
  - James Boggs, Mar 29, 1983; cuid1196 (Box 1, Cassette 22, Box 12, Cd J. Boggs 1, Cassette 177 C)
    Interview covers Boggs' youth in the South, factory life in Detroit during the 1930s-1940s, the Johnson-Forest Tendency, and activities in 1960s-1970s.
  - James Boggs, Aug 6, 1986; cuid1197 (Box 10, Cassette 421 A-B, Box 12, Cd J. Boggs 2-3)
    Interview regarding Boggs' involvement in the Johnson-Forest Tendency.
  - Paul Booth, Oct 1969; cuid1198 (Box 10, Cassette 422, Box 12, Cd Booth 1-2)
    Interview discusses Students for a Democratic Society, its internal politics, relationships with other student groups, and demonstrations.
    Interview by Kirkpatrick Sale.
  - Frank Bohn, Mar 1, 1958; cuid1199 (Box 12, Cd Bohn 1, Box 1, Cassette 24)
    Interview includes Bohn's memories of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Thomas Hagerty, the Catholic church, and the Socialist Labor Party.
  - Fannie Borun, Jan 6, 1981; cuid1200 (Box 1, Cassette 25, Box 12, Cd Borun 1)
    Political struggles within the International Ladies Garment Workers Union during the 1920s, experiences on trips in the Soviet Union during the 1930s, and women's role in the Communist Party.
    Interview by Bea Lemisch.
    Duration: 63 minutes
  - Judy Boudon, Feb 7-8, 1982; cuid1201 (Box 7, Folder 7, Box 12, Cd Boudon 1-2, Box 1, Cassette 26 A-B)
    Interview includes discussion of Boudon's immigration from Panama, the Spanish-language immigrant community in New York during the 1930s, her work in offices and factories, the America Labor Party, the Communist Party, and women's role in the CP.
  - Thomas Brandon, Nov 4, 1976; cuid1202 (Box 1, Cassette 27, Box 10, Box 12, Cd Brandon 1-2)
    Interview covers the Workers' Newsreel and Film and Photo League during the early 1930s.
    Interview by Russell Campbell.
    Duration: 85 minutes; Preservation note: Muffled sound/low volume
  - Miriam Braverman, Nov 8, 1984; cuid1203 (Box 81, Cassette 364, Box 12, Cd Braverman 1)
  - Jeremy Brecher, Mar 31, 1970; cuid1204 (Box 12, Cd Brecker 1-2, Box 1, Cassette 28)
    Brecher discusses the activities of the Students for a Democratic Society between 1962 and 1965.
  - George Breitman, Jan 4, 1979; cuid1205 (Box 12, Cd Breitman 1-3, Box 1, Cassette 29 A-C)
    Interview covers the activities of unemployed organizations in New Jersey and the Socialist Workers Party between 1938 and 1954.
  - Harry Brier, Aug 26, 1983; cuid1206 (Box 1, Cassette 30, Box 12, Cd Brier 1)
    Brier discusses life in the East End of London during the 1920s-1930s, the Jewish character of Communism, anti-fascist activities in London during the 1920-1930s, his immigration to Los Angeles, and union activities, from the 1940s to the time of the interview.
  - Theodore Brise, Apr 18, 1980; cuid1207 (Box 13, Cd Brise 1, Box 1, Cassette 31)
    Interview contains discussion of anarchism and Arbeter Ring in Los Angeles, Yiddish anarchist activists, and the Rudolf Rocker Circle.
    Duration: 45 minutes
  - Brookwood Labor College, Oct 10, 1982; cuid1208 (Box 13, Cd Brookwood 1-4, Box 1, Cassette 32 A-D)
    Recording of a slide show on the history of Brookwood Labor College and Workers' Education Local 189, with comments by former Brookwood staff and students.
    Narrated by Jon Bloom.
  - Niki Brorsen, May 20, 1975; cuid1209 (Box 1, Cassette 33 A-B, Box 13, Cd Brorsen 1-2)
    Interview contains discussion of Brorsen's family background and growing up in San Francisco and Chicago during the 1950s-1960s, the anti-war work, and Brorsen's decision to join the Young Socialist Alliance during the late 1960s. It also addresses her work as a waitress and activities in restaurant union during the 1970s.
    Duration: 119 minutes in two parts
  - Peter Buch, Aug 24, 1976; cuid1210 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Interview documents Buch's immigration from Turkey and youth in Los Angeles, brief involvement in Socialist Zionism during the early 1950s, the Socialist Workers Party and Young Socialist Alliance in Los Angeles and nationally during the 1950s-1960s, the Robert Williams case, responses to Cuban Revolution, and the Vietnam War.
    Interview by Douglas Cooper.
  - Heinz Buergers, Apr 26, 1980; cuid1211 (Box 13, Cd Buergers 1, Box 2, Cassette 39)
    Interview by Beth Haskell.
  - David Burbank, Oct 6, 1984; cuid1212 (Box 1, Cassette 35, Box 13, Cd Burbank 1)
    Interview contains discussion of Saint Louis radicalism during the 1930s, the Socialist Party, the American Workers Party, the Trotskyist movement, and the Workers Party. Also discussed is CLR James in Missouri and unionization of gas workers.
  - Ann Burlak Timpson, Dec 18, 1980; cuid1213 (Box 13, Cassette Burlak-Timpson 1-5, Box 2, Cassette 35.1 A-E)
    Interview covers Burlak Timpson's labor activities in Rhode Island and Communist activities during the 1930s-1940s.
    Duration: 257 minutes in five parts
  - Ann Burlak Timpson, 1977; cuid1214 (Box 13, Cd Burlak-Timpson 6, Box 2, Cassette 36)
    This talk covers labor activities in Rhode Island during the early 1930s and her role as a Communist speaker, and organizer in Providence and Pawtucket.
    Public address, Rhode Island Labor History Forum.
    Duration: 20 minutes; Preservation note: Audio quality is very poor.
  - C., Pete, undated; cuid1215 (Box 13, Box 7, Folder 9, Box 10, Cassette 427 A-B)
    This interview with a Detroit-based socialist, includes a description of his background, the appeal of socialism, and his involvement with the Teamsters.
    Interview by Sam Friedman.
  - James P. Cannon, undated; cuid1216 (Box 13, Cd Cannon 1, Box 10, Cassette 413, Box 7, Folder 10)
    Recording of speech titled "What Socialist America Will Look Like."
  - Fanny and Herman Cantor, Jan 11, 1979; cuid1217 (Box 13, Cd Cantor 1, Box 2, Cassette 37)
    Interview covers immigration to US from Russia and development of social consciousness, growing up in Hell's Kitchen in New York, radicalism and cooperativism during the 1920s-1930s, and reflections on younger radicals and current events at the time of the interview.
    Interview by Milton Cantor.
  - Philip Caplowitz, Nov 15, 1980; cuid1218 (Box 13, Cassette Caplowitz 1-2, Box 2, Cassette 38 A-B)
    Interview covers Caplowitz's immigration, the activities of Jewish Communists in unions during the 1920s-1930s, and Yiddish culture and the Yiddishe Kultur Farband during the 1930s-1980s.
    Duration: 77 minutes in two parts
  - Wendell Carroll, Nov 30, 1983; cuid1219 (Box 2, Cassette 39 A-B, Box 7, Folder 11, Box 13, Cd Carroll 1-2)
    Interview covers the activities of American Youth for Democracy during the late 1940s, the Independent Socialist League during the early 1950s, ISL positions on the Korean War, the Rosenberg case, the Communist Party and McCarthyism, and race and civil rights.
    Duration: 104 minutes in two parts
  - Pincus Caruso, Mar 16, 1983; cuid1220 (Box 7, Folder 12, Box 2, Cassette 40 A-B, Box 13, Cd Caruso 1-2)
    Interview covers the origins of Labor (Paole) Zionism in Eastern Europe and Caruso's role in the early 20th century; the formation and publication Yiddishe Kempfer in New York; the growth of Poale Zionism during the World War I era and brief publication of daily Zionist newspaper; growth of Zionism in the 1930s-1940s and support of Israel; and reflections on the failure of Zionists regarding Arabs in Israel and the conservative Israeli leadership.
    Duration: 88 minutes in two parts
  - Catholic Worker Conference, May 2, 1983; cuid1221 (Box 13, Cd Catholic Worker Conference 1-2, Box 2, Cassette 41 A-B)
    Program held at Trinity College in Worcester, Massachusetts to honor Dorothy Day and founding of the Catholic Worker. Includes panel comments by John Cort and others regarding Day and the Catholic Worker.
  - Reverend Don Chase, Nov 5, 1983; cuid1222 (Box 13, Cd Chase 1-2, Box 2, Cassette 44 A-B)
    Interview documents activities against the United States' intervention in Nicaragua in 1928, Christian Socialism in a San Francisco parish during the 1930s-50s, and Chase's interpretation of the Liberation Theology of the 1970s-80s.
  - Bernard Chazanow, April 26, 1977; cuid1223 (Box 13, Cd Chazanow 1, Box 2, Cassette 42)
    Interview documents Chazanow's role as a political activist in Russia from 1898-1909 and the activities of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) from 1909-1928.
    Duration: 54 minutes
  - Bernard Chazanow, May 31, 1978; cuid1224 (Box 7, Folder 13, Box 13, Cassette Chazanow 2-4, Box 2, Cassette 43 A-C)
    This recording contains an interview to supplement Chazanow's 1956 Yiddish autobiography, Days and Years.
    Preservation Note: Incubation was attempted on these audiocassettes, however they could not be digitized due to their condition.
  - Rose Chernin, Oct 25, 1983; cuid1225 (Box 7, Folder 14, Box 2, Cassette 45, Box 1, Cd Chernin 1)
    Interview documents the origins and activities of the Los Angeles branch of the Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born during the 1940s-1950s, Chernin's family life, and her relationship with her daughter.
  - Harold Christoffel, Jun 27, 1974; cuid1226 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Interview documents the early union background of former president of United Auto Workers Local 248 Allis Chalmers in Milwaukee, Wisconsin during the 1930s.
    Interview by Roger Keeran.
  - Helen Ciminelli, Joe Richter, and Ann David, Oct 26, 1982; cuid1227 (Box 2, Cassette 47, Box 13, Cd Ciminelli, Richter, David 1)
    Interview covers the activities of SNPJ (Slovenska Narodna Podporna Jednota), a Slovenian mutual aid society, in Fontana, California, during the 1930s-1980s and the SNPJ role in Henry Wallace presidential campaign.
  - Alice Citron, Jan 6, 1981; cuid1228 (Box 2, Cassette 48, Box 13, Cd Citron 1)
    Interview documents Citron's career as a teacher in Harlem during the 1930s-1940s, her involvement in the Teachers' Union, her dismissal during the McCarthy era, and struggle for reinstatement.
  - City College of New York Memorial, Apr 13, 1980; cuid1229 (Box 2, Cassette 46 A-B, Box 13, Cd City College 1-2)
    Recording of a dedication of a memorial for thirteen CCNY alumni members of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade killed in action in the Spanish Civil War. Includes speeches from ALB vets and historians, a recording of a speech by Ernest Hemingway, and musical performances. Speakers include Robert Colodny, Philip Foner, Joseph P. Lash,
  - Egidio Clemente, May 11, 1981; cuid1230 (Box 2, Cassette 50, Box 13, Cd Clemente 1, Box 7, Folder 16)
    Clemente discusses his role as editor of La Parola and secretary of Italian Socialist Federation in the 1930s, Italian left factions in Chicago and other cities, and the left wing Italian presses.
    Interview by Eugene Miller.
  - Lucy Ann Cloud, Aug 25, 1972; cuid1231 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Interview covers the Industrial Workers of the World and Centralia, Washington case of 1919, with particular reference to IWW attorney Elmer Smith.
    Interview by Tom Copeland.
  - Charles Coe, Dec 5, 1991 - Jan 9, 1992; cuid1232 (Box 14, Cd Coe 1-2, Box 80, Cassette 315 A-B)
    Interview by Emily Raphael.
  - Nat Cohen, Nov 5, 1977; cuid1233 (Box 10, Cassette 392, Box 14, Cd N. Cohen 1)
    Discussion of disconnect between Communist Party leadership and working class society. Analysis includes discussion of relationship between leadership and rank and file members; the Party's inability to speak to the broader society's cultural interests; sports; the missed opportunity to engage with Communist movements in communities outside of New York, Chicago, and Los Angeles; and the relationship between art and the Party line.
  - Rose Cohen, Apr 12, 1976; cuid1234 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Recollections of studies at the Jefferson School of Social Science.
  - Joseph Cohen, Ruth Cohen, and Frieda Koren, Jun 9, 1983; cuid1235 (Box 2, Cassette 51, Box 14, Cd Cohen and Koren 1)
    Interview regarding "Carlo" (Jesse Cohen), a cartoonist of the Workers Party during the 1940s.
    Duration: 19 minutes
  - Julia Conroy, May 14, 1980; cuid1236 (Box 2, Cassette 53, Box 14, Cd Conroy 1)
    Interview by Theresa Diamond.
    Duration: 39 minutes
  - Olga Corey, Jan 18, 1983; cuid1237 (Box 2, Cassette 54, Box 14, Cd Corey 1)
    Olga Corey, the daughter of Louis Fraina (Lewis Corey), discusses her reaction to the movie Reds, reminiscences of father at Antioch College during the 1940s, and her own union activities.
    Duration: 42 minutes
  - Carlos Cortez, Jul 25, 1983; cuid1238 (Box 7, Folder 19, Box 2, Cassette 55 A-B, Box 14, Cd Cortez 1-2)
    Cortez discusses being the son of a Mexican-American activist who joined Industrial Workers of the World after San Diego Free Speech Fight, his father's life in Milwaukee during the 1920s, and his mother, a German-American Socialist and poet. Cortez also discusses his imprisonment during World War II as conscientious objector, the role of the IWW in Chicago Mexican-American community during the 1940s, his role as artist and speaker for IWW in the 1940s-1980s, and anarchism and the IWW.
    Duration: 71 minutes
  - Carl Cowl, Mar 13, 1983; cuid1239 (Box 14, Cd Cowl 1-2, Box 2, Cassette 57)
    Duration: 96 minutes
  - Malcolm Cowley, Jan 19, 1981; cuid1240 (Box 14, Cd Cowley 1-2, Box 2, Cassette 56, Box 7, Folder 20)
    Interview covers the Left during the Great Depression, the League of Professional Groups, "Culture and the Crisis" in 1932, the proletarian novel, John Reed Clubs, the Communist Party's Popular Front strategy, the Spanish Civil War, and reflections.
    Interview by Richard Wormser.
  - Roy Curtis, Nov 4, 1984; cuid1241 (Box 80, Cassette 308A-B, Box 14, Cd Curtis 1-3)
    Interview with Roy Curtis of the International Association of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) Local 4.
    Interview by Paul Richiuso.
  - Joseph Cvetas, Oct 22, 1982; cuid1242 (Box 14, Cd Cvetas 1, Box 2, Cassette 58)
    Cvetas discusses his family's background with the Slovenian fraternal society SNPJ (Slovenska Narodna Podporna Jednota), participating in the fraternal society's activities as child, and fraternalism in 1980s.
  - Sam Darcy, 1981; cuid1243 (Box 2, Cassette 59 A-B, Box 14, Cd Darcy 1-3)
    Interview includes a discussion of Darcy's immigrant background, Communist activities during the 1920s, factionalism, Browderism, his departure from the CP, subsequent activities, and reflections.
  - Sam Darcy, Nov 3, 1994; cuid1244 (Box 80, Cassette 342, Box 14, Cd Darcy 4-5)
    Recording of presentation by Sam Darcy at State University of New York at Albany for the course History 3162.
    Existence and Location of Originals
    The original copies of these recordings are held by the University at Albany (SUNY).
  - Sam Darcy, Nov 4, 1994; cuid1245 (Box 80, Cassette 343 A-B, Box 14, Cd Darcy 6-8)
    Recording of presentation by Sam Darcy at the Campus Center Assembly Hall at State University of New York at Albany.
  - Saul Davidson, Mar 16, 1983; cuid1246 (Box 14, Cd Davidson 1, Box 2, Cassette 60)
    Davidson discusses a "United Front" of organizations for preservation of Yiddish language in Miami Beach, his activism in left causes and the preservation of Yiddish, and reflections on survival of the Yiddish language.
  - Sam Davis, Nov 15, 1980; cuid1247 (Box 14, Cd Davis 1-2, Box 2, Cassette 61 A-B)
    Topics discussed include the role of Jewish Left in New Haven, Connecticut since the 1920s, the nature of the Jewish community, the split of Socialists and Communists in the 1920s, the Yiddishe Kultur Farband choir, separation of Morgen Freiheit from the Communist Party, and cultural activities in the YKUF/Jewish Currents circle.
    Duration: 16 minutes; Preservation Note: Due to its condition, one of the audiocassettes could not be digitized.
  - Zoltan Deak, Feb 17, 1983; cuid1248 (Box 7, Folder 21, Box 14, Cd Deak 1, Box 2, Cassette 62)
    Interview includes discussion of the aesthetics of Hungarian-American radical press, including the publications Uj Elore and Hungarian Word from the 1920s-1980s. Interview also includes story of Deak's immigration and his interest in progressive press. Other topics include the circulation and internal structure of Uj Elore, and the shrinking of a distinct Hungarian-American milieu.
  - Jeannette Dean, Apr 14, 1979; cuid1249 (Box 2, Cassette 63, Box 14, Cd Dean 1)
    Dean discusses her family background, union activities, radicalism in unions, and the UE in Newark.
  - Solon De Leon, Dec 16, 1972; cuid1250 (Box 2, Cassette 65 A-C, Box 14, Cd De Leon 1-3)
    Interview includes discussion of the Socialist Party and reformism between 1900-1920, Solon's break with Daniel DeLeon, the International Workers of the World (IWW), the Industrial Union League, and the Socialist Labor Party since the 1930s.
    Interview by Malcolm Kaufman & Jeff Sklar.
    Duration: 178 minutes in three parts; Preservation note: Audio quality very poor
  - Albina Delfino, Jan 8, 1981; cuid1251 (Box 14, Cd Delfino 1-2, Box 7, Folder 22, Box 2, Cassette 66 A-B)
    Interview covers Italian-American women and the Communist Party, the Needle Trades Industrial Union, the National Textile Workers Union, and her experiences as a CP organizer in Lawrence, Providence, Boston, and Corona, New York during the 1930s-1940s.
    Interview with Ruth Prago.
    Duration: 117 in two parts
  - Eugene Dennis Sentence Statement, undated; cuid1252 (Box 14, Cd Dennis 1, Box 80, Cassette 329)
    Statement includes introduction by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn.
  - Esther Dolgoff, Jan 27, 1982; cuid1253 (Box 2, Cassette 67 A-B, Box 7, Folder 23/24, Box 14, Cd Dolgoff 1-2)
    Dolgoff discusses anarchist women of the 1930s and the character of anarchism. Transcription is incomplete.
    Interview by Bea Limisch.
  - James Dolson, 1979; cuid1254 (Box 2, Cassette 64 A-E, Box 15, Cd Dolson 1-5)
    A series of lectures by Dolson on life and involvement with Communist Party. First two disks are a lecture including Dolson's gravitation to Communism, the Red Scare of the 1920s, Dolson's trial for political beliefs in California, and a question and answer session about Dolson's life and political situation at the time of lecture. Remainder of disks are an interview with Paul Buhle in Providence, Rhode Island. Interview includes Dolson's joining of the Socialist Party in 1907, socialist journals, socialism in Chicago, the trial in California, formation of Communist Labor Party, activism in Pittsburgh in 1930s, the Dies Committee, the state of Israel and the left, and other topics.
  - Bill Dongas, Apr 3, 1983; cuid1255 (Box 2, Cassette 68, Box 15, Cd Dongas 1)
    Dongas describes his experience as a Greek partisan in World War II, immigration struggles during the 1950s, Greek publications, and Radio-Chicago.
    Duration: 77 minutes
  - Dora, Mar 25, 1982; cuid1256 (Box 2, Cassette 69, Box 15, Cd Dora 1)
    The interviewee, going only by her first name, discusses student radicalism during the 1930s, activities of the Communist Party, the United Electrical Workers, and social life and friends.
  - Pauline Dougherty, Jan, 1982; cuid1257 (Box 15, Cd Dougherty 1-4, Box 2, Cassette 70 A-D)